Finding Aid for the Mainerd Baker Collection of Scripts PASC.0274
UCLA Library Special Collections
Mainerd Baker collection of scripts
circa 1940s-1970s
UCLA Library Special Collections
Baker, Mainerd
PASC.0274
3.25 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
Mainerd Baker was a musician and music copyist in Hollywood from the late 1930s through the early 1980s. The collection consists mostly of radio and television scripts either collected by or related to the career of Baker
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of C. Plath, 2003.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9950576893606533
Biography
There is very little biographical information available about Mainerd Baker. He was a musician and music copyist in Hollywood from the late 1930s through the early 1980s. Baker worked at many studios and networks and for many arrangers over the years.
Scope and Content
The collection consists mostly of radio and television scripts related to the career of musician and music copyist Mainerd Baker. The scripts are from productions in which Baker may have been involved with in some capacity and/or scripts that were given to him by friends from the entertainment business who knew of his interest in collecting scripts. Included are scripts from Gulf Screen Guild Theatre, Inner Sanctum Mysteries, and This is Your Life.
Organization and Arrangement
The scripts are arranged alphabetically by program title.
Television scripts.; Radio scripts -- Archives.; Television scripts -- Archives.; Radio scripts; Baker, Mainerd--Archives.
- 1975 Entertainment Hall of Fame Awards (The), 1975 Feb 22 (Box 2)
  General note
  With newspaper clippings.
- 33rd Annual Golden Globe Awards, 1976 Jan 21 (Box 3)
  With program.
- Aldrich Family (The) (Jello Puddings), 1941 Feb 27 (Box 1)
- All-Star Tribute to John Wayne (An), 1976 Nov 06 (Box 3)
- American Film Institute (The), 1975 Feb 09 (Box 2)
  Salute To Orson Welles.
- American Film Institute (The), 1978 Feb 25 (Box 3)
  Salute to Henry Fonda.
- Burns and Allen, 1941 Jan 27 (Box 1)
- Captain Flagg & Sergeant Quirt, 1941 Dec 07 (Box 2)
- Club Matinee, 1941 Feb 13 (Box 1)
- Danny Thomas Preview (The), 1948 June 02 (Box 2)
- Dennis Day Program (The), 1948 Mar 03 (Box 2)
- Everyman's Theatre, 1941 Jan 24 (Box 1)
  Of Human Bondage.
- Everything For The Boys, 1944 Apr 25 (Box 2)
  Death Takes A Holiday.
- Fibber McGee and Molly (Johnson Wax Program), 1940 Nov 19 (Box 1)
- Gang Busters, 1941 Mar 28 (Box 1)
  The Trolley Murders.
- General Foods Company Jello Program, 1942 Mar 15 (Box 1)
- Gulf Screen Guild Theatre, 1941 Dec 14 (Box 1)
  My Life with Caroline.
- Gulf Screen Guild Theatre, 1941 Nov 16 (Box 1)
  Penny Serenade.
- Hallmark Charlotte Greenwood Show (The), 1945 Aug 12 (Box 2)
- I Sing a New World - The Story of Walt Whitman, 1941 Mar 07 (Box 1)
- Inner Sanctum Mysteries, 1941 Feb 25 (Box 1)
  Case of the Blood Toupee.
- Inner Sanctum Mysteries, 1941 Mar 23 (Box 1)
  Man Who Hated Death.
- Julie Andrews Show (The), 1972 Oct 19 (Box 2)
- Kraft Music Hall, 1941 Nov 20 (Box 1)
- Mannix, 1968 Nov 19 (Box 2)
  Killjoy.
- Maxwell House, 1940 Jan 18 (Box 1)
  Good News of 1940.
- Meet Corliss Archer, 1944 Nov 30 (Box 2)
  Corliss Six-Point program.
- Mr. District Attorney, 1941 Feb 26 (Box 1)
  Murder on Commission.
- Naked City, 1962 Apr 03 (Box 2)
  ..And If Any Are Frozen, Warm Them..
- Opening Night, 1963 Aug 23 (Box 2)
- Pepsodent Program (The), 1940 Nov 12 (Box 1)
  Host: Bob Hope.
- Raleigh Cigarette Program, 1943 Jan 24 (Box 1)
- Rexall Drug Store - Durante-Moore Number 39, 1946 Mar 08 (Box 2)
- Route 66, 1962 Apr 13 (Box 2)
  A Feat of Strength.
- Rudy Vallee Program, 1940 Nov 14 (Box 1)
- Saint (The), 1943 Mar 26 (Box 2)
- Screen Directors' Playhouse, 1949 Sept 30 (Box 2)
  Pride of the Yankees.
- Story of Dr. Wassell (The), 1943 Mar 01 (Box 1)
- Suspense, 1944 Jan 13 (Box 2)
  Dime A Dance.
- This Is Your Life - Laurel and Hardy, 1954 Dec 01 (Box 1)
- This Is Your Life - Nanette Fabray, 1971 Oct 10 (Box 1)
- This Is Your Life - Ruth Gordon, 1971 Oct 29 (Box 1)
- Time to Smile, 1941 Apr 16 (Box 1)
- Tree Grows in Brooklyn (A) - Movie Night, 1945 Jan 13 (Box 2)
- Wrigley's Christmas Festival, 1948 Dec 25 (Box 2)